Francisco Vazquez-Gomez Collection 1885-1976(bulk 1907-1920) MS 450
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Francisco Vazquez-Gomez Collection 1885-1976 1907-1920
Collection Number: MS 450
Vazquez-Gomez,Francisco
5.0 linear feet
Personal papers including a Citation Index, news clippings, articles, pamphlets, correspondence, mostly photo stats of materials pertaining to the Mexican Revolution, 1907-1920, during the years of Dr. Francisco Vazquez-Gomez’s political activity. Some original, handwritten materials and 35 millimeter films are included. The bulk of the material consists of copies of newspaper clippings about key figures of the Mexican Revolution, compiled by Dr. Vazquez-Gomez and used in the course of writing his book “Memorias Politicas, 1909-1913”. Biographical material and correspondence of Dr. Francisco Vazquez-Gomez, and his son, Ignacio Vazquez Gomez is included. His son, Dr. Ignacio Vazquez-Gomez continued to add to the research materials through the 1970s. Bulk of the material is in Spanish.
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
None
Francisco Vazquez Gomez Papers 1906-1940, Special Collections Research Center, Southern Illinois University Carbondale.
Biographical Note
Francisco Vazquez-Gomez was born September 23, 1860 in Tula, in the state of Tamaulipas, Mexico, died August 16, 1933 in Mexico City, Mexico. Vazquez-Gomez became a physician in 1889 after attending the National School of Medicine in Mexico City. He served as Minister of Education during the presidency of Porfirio Diaz in addition to being his physician and physician to the Madero family of Coahuila. He married Guadalupe Norma in 1890 and together they had ten children. In 1908 along with his brother, Emilio, he joined the Anti-Reelectionist party that opposed and eventually ousted President Diaz. He supported Francisco Madero and Emiliano Zapata in their respective revolutionary efforts for agrarian reform. He became a candidate for vice-president of Mexico on the 1910 ticket that included Francisco Madero as candidate for president. After a falling out with Madero he was removed as vice-presidential candidate and was assigned as Madero’s representative in Washington, D.C. from 1911 to 1913. He later joined Pascual Orozco and his “Colorados” in their rebellion against Madero. Vazquez-Gomez fell out of favor when Victoriano Huerta had Francisco Madero assassinated and ascended to power. In 1914 he was exiled by Huerta and settled in Bexar County, Texas in the United States where he practiced medicine until 1923. He returned to Mexico in 1923 where he was a Professor of Pathology at the National School of Medicine. He wrote “Memorias Politicas, 1909-1913” about his experiences in the Mexican Revolution which was published in 1933, the year of his death.
This collection is organized into 4 series.
Series I: Research Materials1907-1976
Subseries 1: Citation Index 1906-1958
Subseries 2: Mexican Revolution1907-1976
Subseries 3: People
Subseries 4: Subjects
Series II: Correspondence1911-1965
Subseries 1: Francisco Vazquez-Gomez 1911-1933
Subseries 2: Ignacio Vazquez-Gomez1930-1965
Series III: Biographical Materials1882-1965
Subseries 1: Emilio Vazquez-Gomez1909-1924
Subseries 2: Francisco Vazquez-Gomez1909-1965
Subseries 3: Ignacio Vazquez-Gomez1898-1945
Series IV: Oversize Materials, Films 1885-1914
Citation Index, Research materials, Correspondence, Biographical materials, 35 millimeter film, pamphlets and broadsides. The bulk of the collection is about the Mexican Revolution during the years 1909-1920 compiled by Dr. Francisco Vazquez-Gomez and used to write his book “Memorias Politicas, 1909-1913” which was published in 1933. Many clippings are copies of correspondence in the form of telegrams, some in code, between revolutionaries and key political figures at the time such as Francisco Madero and Venustiano Carranza. There are also articles by and about prominent advocates for social, educational, and agrarian reform such as Jose Vanconcelos, Jose Limantour and Emiliano Zapata. The original collection is at Special Collections Research Center, Southern Illinois University Carbondale “Francisco Vazquez Gomez Papers 1906-1940”
Carranza, Venustiano, 1859-1920; Diaz, Porfirio, 1830-1915; Huerta, Victoriano, 1845-1916; Madero, Francisco I., 1873-1913; Vazquez Gomez, Emilio, 1858-1926; Vazquez Gomez, Francisco, 1860-1933; Vazquez Gomez, Ignacio, b. 1898; Villa, Pancho, 1878-1923; Zapata, Emiliano, 1879-1919; Plan de Ayala (1911)--Broadsides; Plan de la Montana (1885)--Broadsides; Mexico--History--Decena Tragica, 1913; Mexico--History--Revolution, 1910-1920
Container List
- Series I: Research Materials, 1907-1976
  This series is arranged chronologically by Citation Index and Research Materials on the Mexican Revolution, then alphabetically by People, Subjects.
  - Subseries 1: Citation Index, January 1906-1910
    - Citation Index, January 1906-August 1910 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Citation Index, August 1910-February 1911 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Citation Index, January 1914-1952; 1958 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Archivo Octavio Magana Cerda, July-November 1911 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 2: Mexican Revolution, 1907-1976
    - Mexican Revolution, May 1907 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Mexican Revolution, March 1908 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Mexican Revolution, August 1909 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Mexican Revolution, September 1909 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Mexican Revolution, December 1909 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Mexican Revolution, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Mexican Revolution, March 1910 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Mexican Revolution, April 1910 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Mexican Revolution, May 1910 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Mexican Revolution, June 1910 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Mexican Revolution, July 1910 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Mexican Revolution, August 1910 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Mexican Revolution (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Mexican Revolution, October 1910 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Mexican Revolution, November 1910 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Mexican Revolution, December 1910 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Mexican Revolution, January 1911 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Mexican Revolution, February 1911 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Mexican Revolution, March 1911 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Mexican Revolution, April 1-15, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Mexican Revolution, April 16-23, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Mexican Revolution, April 24-30, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Mexican Revolution, May 1-9, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Mexican Revolution, May 10-13, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Mexican Revolution, May 14-19, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Mexican Revolution, May 20-21, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Mexican Revolution, May 22-25, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Mexican Revolution, May 26-31, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Mexican Revolution, June 1911 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Mexican Revolution, July 1-10, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Mexican Revolution, July 11-15, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Mexican Revolution, July 16-19, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Mexican Revolution, July 20-24, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Mexican Revolution, July 25-28, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Mexican Revolution, July 29-31, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Mexican Revolution, August 1-15, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Mexican Revolution, August 16-31, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Mexican Revolution, September 1-3, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Mexican Revolution, September 4-6, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Mexican Revolution, September 7-9, 1911 (Box 2, Fodler 15)
    - Mexican Revolution, September 10-30, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Mexican Revolution, October 1-4, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Mexican Revolution, October 5-8, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Mexican Revolution, October 9-15, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Mexican Revolution, October 16-24, 1911 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Mexican Revolution, October 25-29, 1911 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Mexican Revolution, October 30-31, 1911 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Mexican Revolution, November 1911 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Mexican Revolution, December 1-9, 1911 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Mexican Revolution, December 10-15, 1911 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Mexican Revolution, December 16-25, 1911 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Mexican Revolution, December 26-31, 1911 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Mexican Revolution, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Mexican Revolution, January 1912 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Mexican Revolution, February 1912 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Mexican Revolution, March 1912 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Mexican Revolution, April 1912 (Box 3, Fodler 13)
    - Mexican Revolution, May 1912 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Mexican Revolution, June 1912 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Mexican Revolution, July 1912 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Mexican Revolution, August 1912 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Mexican Revolution, September 1912 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Mexican Revolution, October 1912 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Mexican Revolution, November 1912 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Mexican Revolution, December 1912 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Mexican Revolution, January 1-10, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Mexican Revolution, January 11-31, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Mexican Revolution, February 1-18, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Mexican Revolution, February 19, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Mexican Revolution, February 20-24, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Mexican Revolution, February 25-28, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Mexican Revolution, March 1-15, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Mexican Revolution, March 16-31, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Mexican Revolution, April 1-22, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Mexican Revolution, April 23-30, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Mexican Revolution, May 1-15, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Mexican Revolution, May 16-31, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Mexican Revolution, June 1-15, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Mexican Revolution, June 16-30, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Mexican Revolution, July 1913 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Mexican Revolution, August 1-20, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Mexican Revolution, August 21-31, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Mexican Revolution, September 1913 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Mexican Revolution, October 1913 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Mexican Revolution, November 1913 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Mexican Revolution, December 1913 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Mexican Revolution, January 1914 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Mexican Revolution, February 1914 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Mexican Revolution, March 1914 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Mexican Revolution, April 1-23, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Mexican Revolution, April 24-25,1914 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Mexican Revolution, April 26-28, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Mexican Revolution, April 29-30, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Mexican Revolution, May 1914 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Mexican Revolution, June 1914 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Mexican Revolution, July 1914 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Mexican Revolution, August 1914 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Mexican Revolution, September 1914 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Mexican Revolution, October 1914 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Mexican Revolution, November 1914 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Mexican Revolution, December 1914 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Mexican Revolution, January 1915 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Mexican Revolution, February 1915 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Mexican Revolution, March 1915 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Mexican Revolution, April 1915 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Mexican Revolution, May 1915 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Mexican Revolution, June 1915 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Mexican Revolution, July 1915 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Mexican Revolution, October 1915 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Mexican Revolution, March 1916 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Mexican Revolution, April 1916 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Mexican Revolution, May 1916 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Mexican Revolution, June 1916 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Mexican Revolution, July 1916 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Mexican Revolution, August 1916 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Mexican Revolution, September 1916 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Mexican Revolution, October 1916 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Mexican Revolution, November 1916 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Mexican Revolution, December 1916 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Mexican Revolution, January 1917 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Mexican Revolution, February 1917 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Mexican Revolution, March 1917 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Mexican Revolution, April 1917 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Mexican Revolution, May 1917 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Mexican Revolution, July 1917 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Mexican Revolution, September 1917 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Mexican Revolution, October 1917 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Mexican Revolution, November-December 1917 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Mexican Revolution, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Mexican Revolution, February-April 1918 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Mexican Revolution, July-August 1918 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Mexican Revolution, October-November 1918 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Mexican Revolution, December 1918 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Mexican Revolution, January 1919 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Mexican Revolution, February 1919 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Mexican Revolution, April 1919 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Mexican Revolution, May-June 1919 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Mexican Revolution, July 1919 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Mexican Revolution, August 1919 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Mexican Revolution, September 1919 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Mexican Revolution, October-December 1919 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Mexican Revolution, January 1920 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Mexican Revolution, February 1920 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Mexican Revolution, March-April 1920 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Mexican Revolution, May 1920 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Mexican Revolution, June, August 1920 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Mexican Revolution, October, December 1920 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Mexican Revolution, January-February 1921 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Mexican Revolution, April-May 1921 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Mexican Revolution, June-July 1921 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Mexican Revolution, August-October, December 1921 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Mexican Revolution, January, May, October, November 1922 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Mexican Revolution, December 1923 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Mexican Revolution, January, August 1924 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Mexican Revolution, August 1927 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Mexican Revolution, October 1928 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Mexican Revolution, July 1929 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Mexican Revolution, August, September, November, December 1930 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Mexican Revolution, February 1931 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Mexican Revolution, November 1932 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Mexican Revolution, February, March-June 1933 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Mexican Revolution, April 1934 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Mexican Revolution, June-July, December 1935 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Mexican Revolution, December 1937 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Mexican Revolution, February 1939 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Mexican Revolution, February 1940 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Mexican Revolution, June 1944 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Mexican Revolution, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Mexican Revolution, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Mexican Revolution, June 1949 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Mexican Revolution, November 1951 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Mexican Revolution, November 1952 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Mexican Revolution, July 1953 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Mexican Revolution, April, June 1954 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Mexican Revolution, July-August 1955 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Mexican Revolution, May-June, October 1958 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Mexican Revolution, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Mexican Revolution, July-October 1960 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Mexican Revolution, November 1961 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Mexican Revolution, February-March, August-September 1962 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Mexican Revolution, February-March, August 1963 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Mexican Revolution, June, September, November 1964 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Mexican Revolution, October 1965 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Mexican Revolution, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Mexican Revolution, January-February 1967 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Mexican Revolution, January-February, June, August-October 1969 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Mexican Revolution, March, May 1970 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Mexican Revolution, June-August 1970 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Mexican Revolution, September 1970 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Mexican Revolution, October 1970 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Mexican Revolution, November 1970 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Mexican Revolution, December 1970 (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Mexican Revolution, January-March 1971 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Mexican Revolution, April 1971 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Mexican Revolution, June 1971 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Mexican Revolution, July-November 1971 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Mexican Revolution, March 1973 (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Mexican Revolution, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Subseries 3: People
    - Almazan, Juan Andreu,1891-1965 (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - Barra, Francisco L. de la (Francisco Leon),1863-1939 (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - Barreda, Gabino1818-1881 (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - Beteta, Ramon (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - Cabrera, Luis1876-1954 (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - Calero, Manuel,1868-1929 (Box 6, Folder 59)
    - Carranza, Venustiano,1859-1920 (Box 6, Folder 60)
    - Caso, Antonio1883-1946 (Box 6, Folder 61)
    - Cosio Robelo, Francisco,b. 1880 (Box 6, Folder 62)
    - Huerta, Jorge (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Limantour, Jose Ives,1854-1935 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Madero, Francisco I.,1873-1913 (Box 7, Folder 3-4)
    - Magana, Gildardo,1891-1939 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Martinez, Paulino,1860-1914 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Navarro, Candido,1871-1933 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Obregon, Alvaro,1880-1928 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Reyes, Alfonso,1889-1959 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Sanchez Azcona, Juan1876-1938 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Taracena, Alfonso,1896-1995 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Valades, Jose C.,1901-1976 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Vasconcelos, Jose,1881-1959 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Vazquez-Gomez, Emilio and Francisco,1860-1933 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Zapata, Emiliano,1879-1919 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Subseries 4: Subjects
    - Agrarianism (Box 7, Folder 16-17)
    - Ateneo de la Juventud (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Ciudadela (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Conferencias de Paz (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Corridos (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Constitution of 1917 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Decena Tragica (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Education1910-1959 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Education1960-1971 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Plan de Texcoco(1911) (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Positivism (Box 8, Folder 4-7)
    - Reservas del Tesoro (Treasury Reserves) (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Series II: Correspondence, 1911-1965
  This series is arranged alphabetically by name, then chronologically
  - Subseries 1: Francisco Vazquez-Gomez
    - Francisco Vazquez-Gomez, 1911-1912 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Francisco Vazquez-Gomez, 1914 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Francisco Vazquez-Gomez, 1926 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Francisco Vazquez-Gomez, 1929-1933 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 2: Ignacio Vazquez-Gomez
    - Ignacio Vazquez-Gomez, 1930-1933 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Ignacio Vazquez-Gomez, 1935-1936 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Ignacio Vazquez-Gomez, 1938-1939 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Ignacio Vazquez-Gomez, 1949-1954 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Ignacio Vazquez-Gomez, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Ignacio Vazquez-Gomez, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Ignacio Vazquez-Gomez, 1957, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Ignacio Vazquez-Gomez, 1964-1965 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Series III: Biographical Materials, 1882-1965
  This series is arranged alphabetically by name, personal, professional, then chronological.
  - Subseries 1: Emilio Vazquez-Gomez
    - Various persona documents, 1909-1924 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Subseries 2: Francisco Vazquez-Gomez
    - Personal biographical data (no dates) (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Professional certifications 1882-1928 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Various professional material, 1911-1965 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Subseries 3: Ignacio Vazquez-Gomez
    - Various personal documents, 1898-1945
- Series IV: Oversize Materials, Films 1885-1914
  This series consists of 35 millimeter film about the Mexican Revolution and two braodsides of the Plan de la Montana and the Plan de Ayala.
  - Oversize Broadside: Plan de la Montana (1885) (Box 9)
  - Oversize Broadside: Plan de Ayala (1911) (Box 9)
  - Twelve 35 millimeter films about the Mexican Revolution, 1910-1914 (Box 9)